

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Key Achievements in US Immigration Processes

Successfully managed end-to-end processes for US visa applications and Green Card filings.

LANGUAGES

English	Native	••••
Hindi	Native	••••
Marathi	Advanced	••••

SKILLS

US Immigration · UK Immigration ·

H1B Filing · L1 Filing · Greencard Filing ·

1140 Filing · PERM Filing ·

UK Immigration

PASSIONS



Enjoys playing volleyball.

SANI GUPTA

Immigration and Global Mobility Specialist

SUMMARY

I am a dedicated immigration professional with over 7 years of experience in handling US visas and petition processes. I have a proven track record in filing various visa types and assisting employees with their immigration needs, ensuring a smooth transition for global mobility. I excel in coordinating with stakeholders and providing comprehensive briefing sessions to assignees and employees.

EXPERIENCE

Assistant Manager

10/2018 - Present

CitiusTech Healthcare Technology Pvt. Ltd

Mumbai

Healthcare technology company that provides a range of services and solutions to healthcare organizations.

- Filing H-1B, L-1B (Individual & Blanket) work petitions including Amendment and extension
- Preparing RFE (Request for Evidence) for work petitions and support attorneys with the requirement needed to respond to the application
- Preparing Covering letters, Invitation Letters, Entry Permit, Deputation letters & NOC for Travelers
- · Coordinating between VFS, Consulate and in-house employees for US Visa Interview
- Verify documentation received from employees and guide them as necessary
- · Preparing templates and standardization of the checklist
- · Work with management and recommend the type of visa needed
- Conducting of pre-Visa Interview briefing Sessions for employees scheduled for Interview at the Consulate
- Preparing Weekly and monthly Reports and work towards improvement areas
- · Train new recruits regarding the visa procedures and its related rules
- Preparing Job description for PWD, Filing PERM and guiding employees on the green card process and steps
- Perform data entry and research in various systems and tracking tools.

Associate 12/2015 - 10/2018

Accenture Solutions Private Limited

Mumbai

Global management consulting, technology services, and outsourcing company.

- Handling of visa applications for Business visa for US, UK, Australia, Canada, and other Schengen Countries
- Co-coordinating on work Permits and stamping for US (H1B/H4/B1/L1 & L2)
- Preparation of Covering letters, Invitation Letters to the respective Consulates
- Preparation of NOC for employees for applying for their personal Tourist Visa
- Preparation of Entry Permit for Travelers
- Coordinating between VFS, Consulate and in-house employees for the US Visa Interview
- Scheduling online visa stamping appointments for employees after ensuring completeness and correctness of documents
- · Maintaining reports on daily basis (visa tracker)
- Work with management and recommend the type of visa needed
- Maintaining visa trackers, BEP letters, database updation and visa copy upload for Mumbai Locations

EXPERIENCE

Customer Services Executive

08/2013 - 11/2014

Call to Connect Pvt Ltd

Mumbai

Customer service outsourcing firm.

- Handling the customer query on call.
- Dealing with calls in a highly professional manner
- · How to act as the first point of telephone contact for a customer
- · Handling complaints in a diplomatic way.
- Provide proper information about the product.
- Accurately updating customer records with information.
- Responding to customers who have special communication needs, such as language difficulties or disabilities.
- · Answering any queries quickly and efficiently.
- Quickly understanding a caller's point of view and to empathize with them.
- Fully aware of all laws & regulations regarding data protection.
- Quickly processing information.

EDUCATION

B.Com. (Accounting & Finance)	04/2015 - 04/2015
Bhavans College, Mumbai	Mumbai
H.S.C	03/2012 - 03/2012
Vidyanidhi Jr College , Mumbai	Mumbai

